A Guide to the Alexandria Business and Professional Women's Club Records, 1922-2008
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Alexandria Business and Professional Women's Club Records, 1922-2008
The Library of Virginia
41929
4.05 cu. ft. (11 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
For preservation purposes, please use microfilm for Minute book, 1927-1939 (Misc. reel. 5110).
Acquisition Information
The collection is filed under Accession 41929. Additional materials are donated to the collection periodically.
Gift of Alexandria Business and Professional Women, Lee Perkins, Alexandria, May 2005 (Acc. 41929).
Gift of Alexandria Business and Professional Women, Lee Perkins, Alexandria, December 2006 (Acc. 43008).
Gift of Alexandria Business and Professional Women, Lee Perkins, Alexandria, December 2007 (Acc. 43556).
Gift of Alexandria Business and Professional Women, Lee Perkins, Alexandria, May 2008 (Acc. 43759).
Gift of Alexandria Business and Professional Women, Nancy Suska, Alexandria, June 2008 (Acc. 44903).
Biographical Information
The Alexandria Business and Professional Women's Club is part of the state chapter of Virginia Business and Professional Women's Clubs. The Business and Professional Women's Club was established in 1919 and the Alexandria chapter was organized in 1921. The organizations focus is to achieve equality for all women in the workplace.
Scope and Content
Records, 1922-2008, of the Alexandria Business and Professional Women's Clubs including annual reports, clippings, correspondence, handbooks, membership committee files and directories, minutes, newsletters, photographs, programs, scrapbooks, and yearbooks. Includes copies of the club newsletter, "This 'n That," 1993-2008, "Business Women," 2000-2007, and "Federation Notes," 2001-2008. Included are club handbooks for Officers, Presidents, Committees/Chairs, State officers, and Regional Coordinators. Also includes various programs from meetings and events, 1994-2008, and information on scholarships directed by the organization. Of note is the minute book, 1927-1939, which includes bylaws and constitutions, annual reports, and minutes (use Misc. reel 5110).
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Contents List
- Annual reports, 1922-1938. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Annual reports, 1983-1984. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Annual reports, 1991-1997. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Annual reports, 2000-2001. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Annual reports, 2001-2002. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Annual reports, 2004-2005. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Brochures, undated. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- BPW Foundation, undated. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Certificates, 1992-2003. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Clippings, 1993-2005. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1999-2000. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 2002-2004. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Directory, BPW State Leadership, 1996-1999. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Directory, BPW State Leadership, 2001-2002. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Directory, BPW State Leadership, 2002-2003. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Directory, BPW State Leadership, 2005-2008. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Guest ledger, 1969-1986. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Handbook, 1984. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Handbook, 1999. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- History, Decades of Progress ABPW, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- History, BPW/VA, 1994. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Installation ceremonies, 1991-2000. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Ledger, 1978-1988. (Box 8)
- Membership committee files, 1966. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Membership committee files, 1975-1976. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Membership committee files, 1977-1978. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Membership committee files, 1980-1982. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Membership committee files, 1983-1985. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Membership committee files, 1986-1988. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Membership committee files, 1988-1990. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Membership committee files, 1990-1992. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Membership committee files, 1992-1993. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Membership committee files, 1994-1995. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Membership committee files, 1995-1997. (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
- Membership committee files, 1997-1998. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Membership committee files, 1998-1999. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Minutes, 1927-1939. (Box 7 (also on Misc. reel 5110))
- Minutes, 1993. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Minutes, 2001. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Minutes, 2002. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Minutes, 2003-2005. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Minutes, 2007. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Minutes, 2008. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Newsletters, Business Women, 2000-2005. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Newsletters, Federation Notes, 2001-2005. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Newsletters, Federation Notes, 2006-2008. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Newsletters, Lets Go!, 1927-1928. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Newsletters, Miscellaneous, 2006. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Newsletters, This 'n That, 1993-1995. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Newsletters, This 'n That, 1996. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Newsletters, This 'n That, 1997. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Newsletters, This 'n That, 1998. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Newsletters, This 'n That, 1999. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Newsletters, This 'n That, 2000. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Newsletters, This 'n That, 2001. (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Newsletters, This 'n That, 2002-2003. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Newsletters, This 'n That, 2004. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Newsletters, This 'n That, 2005. (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Newsletters, This 'n That, 2006. (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Newsletters, This 'n That, 2007. (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Newsletters, This 'n That, 2008. (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Photographs, 1993-1998. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Photographs, 2006-2007. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Programs, Conventions, 1996-1997. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Programs, Conventions, 2001-2002. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Programs, Conventions, 2005-2006. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Programs, Conventions, 2008. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Programs, Miscellaneous (breakfasts, spring, banquets), 2002-2005. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Programs, "The Reality Store," 1994-2002. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Programs, "Women of Alexandria," 1999. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Scholarships, 2000-2005. (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Scrapbook, 1976-1977. (Box 9)
- Scrapbook, 1977-1978. (Box 10)
- Scrapbook, 1980. (Box 8)
- Scrapbook, 1982-1983. (Box 11)
- Yearbooks, 1985-1987. (Box 6, Folder 11)